In this last part,
在最后一部分
we're going to want to move all the code that you used in earlier notebooks,
我们将把在之前的 notebook 中用到的所有代码
into a single class that could be used by anyone to easily fit your recommendation,
都移到一个类中 使任何人都能轻松地拟合你的推荐系统
and then make predictions,
然后做出预测
or recommendations to new users.
或向新用户推荐电影
In order to do this,
首先注意
there are few files which you can see over here on the left.
在左侧有几个文件
The file that you'll need to fill in,
你需要填写的文件是
is this recommender_template file.
这个 recommender_template 文件
If we open this,
打开该文件后
you'll notice that there's already a class set up in here.
你会发现 里面已经有一个类
Then you'll notice that it has a Fit method. It has an Init.
还有一个 fit() 方法上面有一个 init() 方法
In case there are any variables you want to pass to your class,
你可以通过该方法向类中传入变量
it has a predict_rating method,
接着是 predict_rating() 方法
and it has a make_recs method.
以及 make_recs() 方法
You'll notice that we also have the train_data.csv,
还有一个 train_data.csv 文件
which has all the reviews data and the movies_clean.csv.
其中包含所有的影评数据 以及一个 movies_clean.csv 文件
I'll just give you a quick glimpse of how your recommender will work once it's all setup.
我简单介绍下设置完毕后推荐系统的运行原理
If we go into Python,
转入 Python 后
you should be able to pull your recommender file from this recommender.py file.
你应该能够从 recommender.py 文件提取推荐系统文件
So, from recommender, I'm going to import this.
我将从 recommender 导入 Recommender
Then, you should be able to instantiate it.
然后实例化 Recommender
So, I didn't actually have anything in my init,
我的 init() 是空的
but you might set yours up in a different way.
不过你的 init() 可能设置不同
Then, essentially the way that I have set my init up,
在我设置 init() 后
was so that it takes the reviews data.
它能够接受影评数据
So, it should take the training data and then will take the movies data.
它应该接受训练数据和电影数据
I just set it up so it will fit our recommender to that training and movies data.
设置好后 它将使 Recommender 拟合训练数据和电影数据
You'll notice, this is using something like what you saw
注意 我使用了之前在奇异值分解部分
before with Singular Value Decomposition using SVD.
用到的类似方法
You'll notice that I'm using the FunkSVD fit portion,
我使用的是 FunkSVD 拟合部分
but you could fit yours using the most popular recommendation.
但是你也可以使用最热门的推荐方法拟合数据
You could fit it based on some content-based recommendation,
或者使用基于内容的推荐方法拟合数据
or you could use the setup that we made in the previous notebook.
或者使用在上个 notebook 中使用的方法拟合数据
There isn't one right answer for this part.
这部分没有一个正确答案
So, while this is running,
这部分代码还在运行
I'm going to give you a quick glimpse of how my recommender file is setup.
我乘机简单介绍下 recommender 文件是如何设置的
I also created this recommender functions file,
我还创建了这个recommender_functions 文件
where I just had a whole bunch of the functions that we wrote,
我们之前编写了大量函数
and I pulled the ones that I needed into this file.
我将需要用到的函数放到了这个文件里
If we look at the recommender functions file,
打开 recommender_functions 文件
you'll notice that I put the get_movie_names function in here.
里面有 get_movie_names 函数
I created the function for create ranked dataframe in here.
我在这里创建了 create_ranked_df 文件
Again, basically, I just copied and pasted
我将之前已经编写的很多函数
a whole bunch of the functions that we had already written into this file,
复制粘贴到了这个文件中
so that I can easily use them in my recommender class.
从而轻松地在 Recommender 类中使用这些函数
If we look at the class file,
打开该类文件
you'll notice I didn't have anything in my setup.
你会发现我的 init() 文件是空的
But then, I wrote a really nice doc string so that it was
但是我写了一段文档字符串
clear for me what my inputs and outputs should be for each one of these.
清晰地注明了每个函数的输入和输出应该是什么
You'll notice that this particular recommendation will have 12 latent features.
这个推荐系统将有 12 个潜在特征
It'll have this learning rate and it should run for a hundred iterations.
学习速率是 0.0001 迭代次数是 100 次
So, we're about halfway done at this point and then after we're done fitting our model,
目前已经完成了一半的任务 拟合模型后
I set it up so that I can easily predict and make
我将能够轻松地使用实例化的这个 Recommender
recommendations using this recommender that I instantiate.
做出预测和推荐电影
Here, I just want to give you a glimpse of each of the methods that are in my class.
下面我将简单介绍下这个类中的每个方法
So, it's really useful to write nice doc strings for each of these methods.
在每个方法中编写这些文档字符串很有用
So that way, if someone else were to use your class,
这样的话 其他人在使用你的类时
they could easily be able to write a question mark after any of your methods,
他们能够在任何方法之后写一个问号
and see what they should be inputting and what they can expect
看看在该类的每个部分
back out for each part of your recommendation class.
输入和输出将是什么
Actually, all of the code that you see within the class,
实际上 在该类中以及 recommender_functions
as well as within the recommender functions,
文件中的所有代码
is basically just code that we use throughout the notebooks.
基本上都是我们在 notebook 中使用的代码
I just put it nicely into a class,
我只是将它们放在了类中
so that it was easily reusable.
便于我们重复利用这些代码
Great. So, we can see that this model isn't
好的可以看出 这个模型并没有
necessarily done fitting to our data in a way where it's converged.
完全拟合数据 因为还没有收敛
It might be useful to run this for longer,
可能还需要运行更长时间
but for the purpose of this demonstration,
但是足以演示
this illustrates how the fit method works.
fit() 方法的原理
Based on that, if you weren't sure how the fit method was run,
如果你还不确定 fit() 方法是如何运行的
we have these doc strings that I wrote into the class.
可以参阅我在类中编写的这些文档字符串
So, it's really easy to see what the inputs should be.
很容易看出输入是什么
You can see that there's no output that should come back from this.
可以看出 没有输出内容
It did print what was happening but there was nothing returned.
的确输出了一条说明所发生情况的消息 但是没有返回任何内容
It created all of these other things,
它创建了这些项
and now each of these should exist on my instantiated object.
现在实例化对象中应该有这些项了
So if we look at, say here,
如果查看 n_users
the n users, we can see how many users were in the dataset.
可以看到数据集中有多少个用户
Or if we look at the number of movies,
如果查看 n_movies
Or we could look at the number of movies,
或者可以查看 n_movies
and you can see how many of those were in the dataset.
可以看到数据集中有多少个电影
Again, the class makes it really easy to pull certain parts.
这个类使我们能够非常轻松地提取某些部分
So, here are all the things that exist.
这些是所有的方法
We should be able to make a recommendation.
我们应该能够做出推荐了
I just remembered that user eight was at the top.
我记得在顶部的是用户 8
Oh sorry. That didn't work.
抱歉出错了
If we look little closer,
再仔细看看
you can see that the default is a movie type.
会发现默认类型是 movie
Let's go back up here.
再回到上面
So, we can enter the ID and then this should be the ID type of user.
输入 ID 这个 ID 类型应该是 user
So, I'm going to change this to user.
我将这个改成 user
Great. Then we can see that these are the five movies that we recommend to that user.
好的我们向此用户推荐了这 5 部电影
You can see that that's the default.
默认推荐数量是 5 部
Again, it's really useful to write a good doc string.
编写清晰的文档字符串很重要
So that you can see exactly what you're supposed to be providing to these methods.
使我们能够完全明白要向这些方法提供什么输入
You can see this with mine.
你可以看看我的文档字符串
I haven't used this for awhile and I wasn't
我已经很长时间没有接触这些代码了
exactly sure why it wasn't working without the doc string.
如果没有文档字符串的话 我都不知道哪里出了问题
I probably wouldn't have been able to figure this out without it.
可能都找不到问题的缘由
I hope this gives you some insight into how you could build your class.
希望你能受到启发 知道如何创建类
There's a lot of flexibility in creating whatever functionality you want into
在向类中添加功能时 你可以灵活处理
your class and making this as extravagant or as simple as you might like.
代码可以很复杂 或很简单